<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sammelsurium on ZN80.NET</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/</link><description>Recent content in Sammelsurium on ZN80.NET</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>de</language><copyright>Copyright © 2021, Carsten Brueggenolte.</copyright><atom:link href="https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Python Virtual Environment</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/python/python-virtualenvironment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/python/python-virtualenvironment/</guid><description>Install virtuelenv via pip3 1 python3 -m pip install virtualenv then check the version
1 2 python3 -m virtualenv --version virtualenv 20.7.2 from /opt/homebrew/lib/python3.9/site-packages/virtualenv/__init__.py Create a Virtual Environment First, let us create a folder .virtualenvs in the home directory. This is where we will keep all our virtual environments.
1 2 3 cd ~ mkdir .virtualenvs cd .virtualenvs From inside the .</description></item><item><title>Speed Up Ssh &amp; Git With This Weird Trick</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/speed-up-ssh-and-git-with-whis-weird-trick/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/speed-up-ssh-and-git-with-whis-weird-trick/</guid><description>This trick helps me saving quite some time when using ssh and git.
I found this on Peter Piekarczyk medium blog.
The difference is quite impressive.
If you’re not using an ssh config file, check out this awesome video explaining the advantages of having one:
# symlink to ~/.ssh/config Host github.com ControlMaster auto ControlPersist 120 Host * # Always use SSH2. Protocol 2 # Use a shared channel for all sessions to the same host, # instead of always opening a new one.</description></item><item><title>The Gemini Protocol</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/misc/gemini-protocol/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/misc/gemini-protocol/</guid><description>Gemini ist ein Protokoll welches Gopher und HTTP angesiedelt ist. Nicht so einfach und simpel wie Gopher, aber definitiv nicht so überladen wie HTML.
Clients Hier eine Auflistung von Clients zum sufen im Gemini-Space:
Lagrange Description: Lagrange is a desktop GUI client for browsing Geminispace. It offers modern conveniences familiar from web browsers, such as smooth scrolling, inline image viewing, multiple tabs, visual themes, Unicode fonts, bookmarks, history, and page outlines.</description></item><item><title>TiddlyWiki</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/misc/tiddlywiki/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/misc/tiddlywiki/</guid><description>Tiddlywiki Server mit Basis Authentification starten Endlich habe ich Tiddlywiki so umgestellt, dass in der Befehlszeile die Passwörter und Benutzernamen nicht mehr angezeigt werden. Somit ist auch das Password aus der ps / htop Prozessübersicht verschwunden.
Anstelle Benutzername und Passwort als Parameter 1 zu übergeben, erstellt man sich eine eine .csv-Datei erstellt und schreibt dort alle Benutzernamem und Passwörter rein 2. Anschließend starten wir Tiddlywiki mit folgendem Befehl:
1 2 3 4 5 tiddlywiki $HOME/tiddlywiki/personal --listen host=0.</description></item><item><title>Lowercase all filename in a directory with one line of code</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/lowercase-all-filenames-in-a-directory/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/lowercase-all-filenames-in-a-directory/</guid><description>Here’s a one-liner you can use to change all the filenames that include uppercase letters to lowercase. If I didn’t write about it, I’d forget how it works, so here we go!
1 for f in *; do echo $f; mv $f $(echo $f | tr &amp;#39;[:upper:]&amp;#39; &amp;#39;[:lower:&amp;#39;]); done Break down:
for file in *: loops over every file (variable). You could also do in *.pdf and that would only select PDF’s for example</description></item><item><title>What should be used in ZSH on a Mac</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/zsh-on-macos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/zsh-on-macos/</guid><description>I posted a more narrowly scoped question on Unix &amp;amp; Linux and got some clarification on how these files &amp;ldquo;work.&amp;rdquo; Here&amp;rsquo;s the summary of that answer and what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned in my research as to what, in my opinion should be used in a ZSH environment on a Mac.
.zprofile .zlogin and .zprofile are basically the same thing - they set the environment for login shells; they just get loaded at different times (see below).</description></item><item><title>Installation von Virtualbox auf Manjaro Linux</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/installation-virtualbox-manjaro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/installation-virtualbox-manjaro/</guid><description>VirtualBox lässt sich sehr einfach mithilfe des Paketmanagers &amp;ldquo;Add/Remoe Software&amp;rdquo; installieren. pamac-manager wird da ausgeführt. Schneller geht es aber im Terminal
Vorraussetzung: In den Settings muss der AUR-Support aktiviert sein.
Finde deine Kernelversion mit mwhd-kernel -li
1 2 3 4 $ mhwd-kernel -li Currently running: 5.10.36-2-MANJARO (linux510) The following kernels are installed in your system: * linux510 Installieren: Führe folgenden Befehl aus um die nötigen Pakete zu installieren</description></item><item><title>The best way to store your dotfiles: A bare Git repository</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/configs/the-best-way-to-store-your-dotfiles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/configs/the-best-way-to-store-your-dotfiles/</guid><description>Disclaimer: This post is heavily based on the one at https://www.atlassian.com/git/tutorials/dotfiles which goes more into the details
Some other sources you might want to check out:
Hacker News thread on people&amp;rsquo;s solutions to store their dotfiles. User StreakyCobra showed his elegant setup The only pre-requisite is to install Git.
In his words the technique below requires:
No extra tooling, no symlinks, files are tracked on a version control system, you can use different branches for different computers, you can replicate you configuration easily on new installation.</description></item><item><title>Pastebins</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/pastebins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/pastebins/</guid><description>Text und Ausgaben teilen mithilfe von Pastebins
https://termbin.com/ echo just testing! | nc termbin.com 9999 cat ~/some_file.txt | nc termbin.com 9999 ls -la | nc termbin.com 9999 Aliases fish / bash:
# termbin alias tb=&amp;quot;nc termbin.com 9999&amp;quot; envs.sh | THE NULL POINTER HTTP POST files here:
curl -F'file=@yourfile.png' https://envs.sh post your text directly:
echo &amp;quot;text here&amp;quot; | curl -F'file=@-;' https://envs.sh you can also POST remote URLs:</description></item><item><title>Linux Tools</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/tools/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/tools/</guid><description>Einige Linuxprogramme die mir aufgefallen sind:
alacritty - terminal manager Variety - Variety changes the wallpaper on a regular interval using user-specified or automatically downloaded images. https://launchpad.net/variety</description></item><item><title>VS Code Config</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/configs/vs-code/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/configs/vs-code/</guid><description>This is how I setup my VS Code. I mostly use it for reading/writing markdown and Go.
Quick Start Guide Extensions Go golangci-lint Go Snippets Markdown All in One Table of Content MarkdownLint GitLens LanguageTool for Visual Studio Code Code Spell Checker VS Notes General Settings Disable git Markdown Settings Word Separator Note Creating Snippets Note: This guide is heavily inspired by https://parsiya.</description></item><item><title>Move Your Home Folder To A Second Drive</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/move-your-home-folder-to-a-second-drive/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 15:44:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/move-your-home-folder-to-a-second-drive/</guid><description>This page is a copy of DTs page at https://distrotube.com/articles/move-your-home-folder-to-second-drive.html
Make Reinstalling Faster By Having Home On A Second Drive
Note: You may want to drop into tty to perform the following to avoid any weird side effects from doing this within your graphical environment. Also, for this example we will assume that your partition is sdb1 (change this to the id of your drive!). Also, have a backup handy — just in case.</description></item><item><title>Forward remote port of remote machine to local port through SSH</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/forward-remote-port-of-remote-machine-to-local-port-through-ssh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/forward-remote-port-of-remote-machine-to-local-port-through-ssh/</guid><description>Verwende diesen Befehl auf deinem lokalen Rechner, um den Port 8000 des entfernten Rechners 192.168.0.1 zu deinem lokalen Rechner an Port 8000 zu tunneln:
ssh -L 8000:192.168.0.1:8000 root@192.168.0.1</description></item><item><title>How to use Hugo data files</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/hugo/how-to-use-hugo-data-files/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/hugo/how-to-use-hugo-data-files/</guid><description>Hugo Data Files lassen sich wie folgt verwenden.
Data Dateien werden im data Verzeichnis abglegt und werden in den Templates über .Site.Data.&amp;lt;DateiName&amp;gt; angesprochen. Die Verzeichnisstruktur innerhlab von Data muss eingehalten werden. Mehr Informationen zu den Data-Templates gibt es hier: https://gohugo.io/templates/data-templates/#readout
Im Verzeichnis data legst du dateien im format json,toml oder yaml ab. Das Format und der Inhalt ist dir überlassen. Als Beispiel habe ich hier eine Bookmark-Liste. Diese Datei könnte sich hier befinden: data/bookmarks/windows.</description></item><item><title>Setting Alt-Tab behavior in gnome-shell</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/setting-alt-tab-behavior-in-gnome-shell/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/setting-alt-tab-behavior-in-gnome-shell/</guid><description>After switching to gnome updating my distro a few months ago, I somehow lost my tweaks to the Alt-Tab behavior in gnome-shell.
The default is to have Alt-Tab switch you between applications in the current workspace. One can use Alt-backtick (or whatever key you have above Tab) to switch between windows in the current application.
I prefer a Windows-like setup, where Alt-Tab switches between windows in the current workspace, regardless of the application to which they belong.</description></item><item><title>Beheben von Problemem mit NVMEs und einfrierenden Desktops</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/fixing-nvmes-issues/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/fixing-nvmes-issues/</guid><description>Hinweis 2021-06-07: Das Problem scheint nur Debian basierte System zu betreffen. Weder Manjaro noch ArcoLinux sind eingefroren.
Da meine Pop!_OS Installation immer wieder eingefroren ist, habe ich mich nach Lösungen umgeschaut und zwei Lösungen gefunden. Lösung 1 hat bei mir leider nicht funktioniert und es scheint so, dass Arch basierte System nicht betroffen sind. (Oder liegt es am Kernel?)
Problem: Ab und zu und ohne Vorwarnung, friert das System einfach ein und lässt sich nicht mehr bedienen.</description></item><item><title>Comments For Static Sites</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/webdevelopment/comments-for-static-sites/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/webdevelopment/comments-for-static-sites/</guid><description>https://remark42.com/ https://utteranc.es/
A lightweight comments widget built on GitHub issues. Use GitHub issues for blog comments, wiki pages and more! https://web.hypothes.is/
Annotate the web, with anyone, anywhere. http://commento.io/
Embed comments in your website to foster discussion and increase engagement. https://just-comments.com/
JustComments is a public comment system. It works for every website. Perfect for the static ones. https://www.talkyard.io/blog-comments
Talkyard is a commenting system for your website. https://comment.sh/
Lightweight hosted comments powered by Isso http://docuss.</description></item><item><title>Meine Firefox Add-ons</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/configs/meine-firefox-add-ons/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/configs/meine-firefox-add-ons/</guid><description>Die Mozilla-Foundation macht sich mit ihrer aktuellen Entlassungsaktion gerade nicht sehr beliebt (siehe hier, hier, und hier), ist und bleibt aber trotzdem – neben Safari – mein Lieblingsbrowser. Und weil das so ist, habe ich hier ein paar Empfehlungen für dich. Die meisten stehen zwar auch auf der Liste der Empfehlungen von Mozilla, aber das macht ja nichts. 😉
Zuletzt habe ich diese Liste am 26.11.2020 aktualisiert.</description></item><item><title>Quotes</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/quotes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/quotes/</guid><description>Quotes and mottos from random people:
Unknow origin mottos:
We make shitty software, with bugs! People return to places that send them away. It&amp;rsquo;s even worse than it appears. Still diggin. So it has come to this. Let&amp;rsquo;s have fun! Only steal from the best. Narrate your work. Sources go direct.</description></item></channel></rss>