<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sammelsurium on ZN80.NET</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/</link><description>Recent content in Sammelsurium on ZN80.NET</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>de</language><copyright>Copyright © 2021, Carsten Brueggenolte.</copyright><atom:link href="https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VS Code Config</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/configs/vs-code/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/configs/vs-code/</guid><description>This is how I setup my VS Code. I mostly use it for reading/writing markdown and Go.
Quick Start Guide Extensions Go golangci-lint Go Snippets Markdown All in One Table of Content MarkdownLint GitLens LanguageTool for Visual Studio Code Code Spell Checker VS Notes General Settings Disable git Markdown Settings Word Separator Note Creating Snippets Note: This guide is heavily inspired by https://parsiya.</description></item><item><title>Move Your Home Folder To A Second Drive</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/move-your-home-folder-to-a-second-drive/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 15:44:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/move-your-home-folder-to-a-second-drive/</guid><description>This page is a copy of DTs page at https://distrotube.com/articles/move-your-home-folder-to-second-drive.html
Make Reinstalling Faster By Having Home On A Second Drive
Note: You may want to drop into tty to perform the following to avoid any weird side effects from doing this within your graphical environment. Also, for this example we will assume that your partition is sdb1 (change this to the id of your drive!). Also, have a backup handy — just in case.</description></item><item><title>Forward remote port of remote machine to local port through SSH</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/forward-remote-port-of-remote-machine-to-local-port-through-ssh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/forward-remote-port-of-remote-machine-to-local-port-through-ssh/</guid><description>Verwende diesen Befehl auf deinem lokalen Rechner, um den Port 8000 des entfernten Rechners 192.168.0.1 zu deinem lokalen Rechner an Port 8000 zu tunneln:
ssh -L 8000:192.168.0.1:8000 root@192.168.0.1</description></item><item><title>How to use Hugo data files</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/hugo/how-to-use-hugo-data-files/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/hugo/how-to-use-hugo-data-files/</guid><description>Hugo Data Files lassen sich wie folgt verwenden.
Data Dateien werden im data Verzeichnis abglegt und werden in den Templates über .Site.Data.&amp;lt;DateiName&amp;gt; angesprochen. Die Verzeichnisstruktur innerhlab von Data muss eingehalten werden. Mehr Informationen zu den Data-Templates gibt es hier: https://gohugo.io/templates/data-templates/#readout
Im Verzeichnis data legst du dateien im format json,toml oder yaml ab. Das Format und der Inhalt ist dir überlassen. Als Beispiel habe ich hier eine Bookmark-Liste. Diese Datei könnte sich hier befinden: data/bookmarks/windows.</description></item><item><title>Setting Alt-Tab behavior in gnome-shell</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/setting-alt-tab-behavior-in-gnome-shell/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/setting-alt-tab-behavior-in-gnome-shell/</guid><description>After switching to gnome updating my distro a few months ago, I somehow lost my tweaks to the Alt-Tab behavior in gnome-shell.
The default is to have Alt-Tab switch you between applications in the current workspace. One can use Alt-backtick (or whatever key you have above Tab) to switch between windows in the current application.
I prefer a Windows-like setup, where Alt-Tab switches between windows in the current workspace, regardless of the application to which they belong.</description></item><item><title>Fixing NVMEs Issues</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/fixing-nvmes-issues/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/linux/fixing-nvmes-issues/</guid><description>Fixing NVMe Issues in Linux sudo kernelstub -a nvme_core.default_ps_max_latency_us=0
https://tekbyte.net/2020/fixing-nvme-ssd-problems-on-linux/</description></item><item><title>Comments For Static Sites</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/webdevelopment/comments-for-static-sites/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/webdevelopment/comments-for-static-sites/</guid><description>https://remark42.com/ https://utteranc.es/
A lightweight comments widget built on GitHub issues. Use GitHub issues for blog comments, wiki pages and more! https://web.hypothes.is/
Annotate the web, with anyone, anywhere. http://commento.io/
Embed comments in your website to foster discussion and increase engagement. https://just-comments.com/
JustComments is a public comment system. It works for every website. Perfect for the static ones. https://www.talkyard.io/blog-comments
Talkyard is a commenting system for your website. https://comment.sh/
Lightweight hosted comments powered by Isso http://docuss.</description></item><item><title>Meine Firefox Add-ons</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/configs/meine-firefox-add-ons/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/configs/meine-firefox-add-ons/</guid><description>Die Mozilla-Foundation macht sich mit ihrer aktuellen Entlassungsaktion gerade nicht sehr beliebt (siehe hier, hier, und hier), ist und bleibt aber trotzdem – neben Safari – mein Lieblingsbrowser. Und weil das so ist, habe ich hier ein paar Empfehlungen für dich. Die meisten stehen zwar auch auf der Liste der Empfehlungen von Mozilla, aber das macht ja nichts. 😉
Zuletzt habe ich diese Liste am 26.11.2020 aktualisiert.</description></item><item><title>Quotes</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/quotes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/sammelsurium/quotes/</guid><description>Quotes and mottos from random people:
Unknow origin mottos:
We make shitty software, with bugs! People return to places that send them away. It&amp;rsquo;s even worse than it appears. Still diggin. So it has come to this. Let&amp;rsquo;s have fun! Only steal from the best. Narrate your work. Sources go direct.</description></item></channel></rss>