<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>New York on ヾ(＾-＾)ノ ZN80.NET</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/tag/new-york/</link><description>Recent content in New York on ヾ(＾-＾)ノ ZN80.NET</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>de-DE</language><copyright>Copyright © 2021, Carsten Brueggenolte.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 20:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cblte.github.io/tag/new-york/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New York City und das Corona Virus</title><link>https://cblte.github.io/2020/11/new-york-city-und-das-corona-virus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cblte.github.io/2020/11/new-york-city-und-das-corona-virus/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ist zwar schon etwas älter, aus dem August, aber trotzdem gut und ganz interessant anzuschauen wie das Corona-Virus die Stadt New York innerhalb ovn 5 Monaten verändert haben. Wie es da wohl heute aussieht?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/08/07/style/coronavirus-nyc-historic-season.html">Die New York Times schreibt:&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A Season of Grief and Release: 5 Months of the Virus in New York City. A photographic timeline of a historic half-year. Photographs by Daniel Arnold, Text by Dodai Stewart&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The restaurant was empty, save for two other tables. Spoons slid through our dessert, split three ways. We were anxious but determined to enjoy it, somehow. It was March 10, and the coronavirus had just hit New York City. We laughed, but with worry in our brows and the preamble of panic in our eyes. The next day, I packed up my desk at work: the computer, the mouse, the keyboard. I left the giant monitor and two boxes of Girl Scout cookies behind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The city has changed, the people have changed. The country has changed. The world has changed. We walk outside masked, coated in a residue of terror and grief.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Auch hier in Deutschland, den Niederlanden und im Rest von Europa hat sich vieles verändert durch das Corona-Virus. Es wird noch eine Weile dauern, bis sich alles wieder normalisiert hat. Doch bis dahin, drücken wir die Daumen, dass das der Impfstoff funktioniert und wir das kleine Fiese Dinge bekämpfen können.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>